ふんふん… ふん！
絶対 信じないからな！
仮にも ｵﾚ 主人公だよ｡
怖くないぞ～ 怖いもんか！
あれ？ 動けない… ふっ！
うぅ～ ﾀﾞﾒだ！
かつては 白夜叉とかいって
ﾌﾞｲﾌﾞｲ ｳﾞｨｸﾄﾘｰ言わせてたんだよ！
まさか れ… 霊の仕業か？ これ｡
あれ？ おい まさか…
ひょっとして これ 金縛り？
まさか…
ｵﾚは そういうの信じないからな｡
金縛りなのか？
えっ な… 何？ これ｡
霊が怖いなんて
ﾊｯ… そんな ｱﾊﾊﾊ…｡
(銀時)うっ… うぅっ…｡
《ﾊｯ… はぁ… 夢か｡
(銀時の寝息)
おぉ～い 神楽！ って
声 出てないよ｡
ｵﾚ しゃべってるのに
おぉ～い！ おぉ～い!!
ﾊｧﾊｧ… 息苦しい…
なんか息苦しいよ｡
やっぱ霊か…
こりゃ 霊の仕業か？
っつうか 前言撤回！
ｵﾚ やっぱ 霊 信じるわ｡
It's a d-d-dream...
おい 誰か そこにいるの？ いや…
霊さん いらっしゃるんですか？
Huh? I can't move.
ｵﾚが悪かった…
誰か 金縛り といて！
頼む！ 頼みます!!
助けて！ お願いします!!
It's no use...
助けてくださ～い！》
Huh? Could it be?
Could it be kanashibari? Is it kanashibari?
[Note: Kanasibari means to be bound and paralyzed by a ghost.]
Huh? Wh-Wh-What's going on?
Nah, can't be...
C-C-Could it be ghosts...
Ohh...I don't believe in that. I absolutely don't believe in that.
I'm not afraid. How can I be... I'm the star.
Once upon a time, I was called the White Demon and the people were afraid of me.
I can't be afraid of a ghost.
Hey, Kagura! I have no voice? I'm talking, but nothing's coming out.
Hey! Hey! I'm having trouble breathing. I'm struggling to breathe.
Is it a ghost, after all? Is it the ghost's doing?
I take back what I said. I do believe in ghosts!
Hey, is someone there? Ghost, are you there?
I was wrong. So please release me from the ghost paralysis. Please! I'm begging you!
Help! Help me please!
[For some reason, Gin-san is frozen by ghost paralysis and incapable of moving.]
[Is it the work of ghosts? And when will he ever be released?]
Hey, it's morning...
《おいおい 朝になっちまったよ｡
動けないまま まんじりともせず｡
I can't move... I haven't moved...
ひょっとして
ｵﾚ このまま ずっと動けないの？
Am I going to be like this for the rest of my life?
霊さん！ 返事してくれよ!!
Ghost-san, please answer me! Ghost-san! Ghost-san! Ghost-san!
霊さん！ 霊さん!! 霊さ～ん！》
(新八)おはようございます｡
《ﾊｯ 新八だ！
Good morning.
Oh, Shinpachi. Shinpachi! Help me!
新八！ 助けてくれ!!
Shinpachi. Shinpachi! Shinpachi!
新八 新八… 新八～！
って 声 出てないよ｡
My voice isn't coming out. I'm talking, but I have no voice.
ｵﾚしゃべってるのに
声 出てないよ》
(神楽)ふぁ～あ… 新八 おはよう｡
《神楽！
Morning, Shinpachi.
Kagura...it doesn't matter who... Save me. Save me. Please. Save me.
誰でもいい 助けて！
助けて お願い!!
You look sleepy. Morning, Kagura-chan.
Huh? Where's Gin-chan? Is Gin-chan still asleep?
助けて！》
(神楽)あれ？ 銀ちゃんは？
That's right. Gin-san's suffering from ghost paralysis.
(神楽)銀ちゃん まだ寝てるｱﾙか？
《銀さん ここで
金縛りにあってるんだよ！》
(神楽)私 起こしてくるｱﾙか？
《だから 早く来て！》
Shall I wake him up?
Hurry and come here!
No, never mind. Gin-san's in kanashibari.
あぁ いい いい！ 銀さん
今 金縛りにあってるから｡
《い～っ！ なんで知ってるの？
なんで知ってるの？
What?! How do you know?
知ってて
なんで助けに来ないの？》
How do you know? Why won't you save me even though you know?
(神楽)金縛り？
金縛りって何ｱﾙか？
Kanashibari? What is kanashibari?
金縛りっていうのはね➡
It's a ghost paralysis. You're awake, but your body can't move.
目が覚めてるんだけど
体が動かない状態で➡
ｱﾆﾒ的には すごく楽な状態なんだ｡
It's a very convenient state for the animators.
(神楽)楽？
なんでも ｱﾆﾒｽﾀｯﾌが➡
Convenient?
Seems all the anime staff are taking a trip to Kinugawa Hot Spa,
みんなで 鬼怒川温泉に
旅行に行くんで➡
今日は
｢銀さんの金縛りにあう｣の巻で➡
so they were talking about creating a 30-minute "Gin-san Meets Ghost Paralysis" episode.
30分 作っちゃおう
っていう話だよ｡
《えぇ～っ!?》
What?!
["Gin-san Meets Ghost Paralysis"]
そんなわけ あるか～！
You can't do that!
Oh, I'm free of the ghost paralysis.
あっ やった！ 金縛り とけた!!
ふぅ… っつうか ｱﾆﾒｽﾀｯﾌ！
Anime staff! You think you can get away with such laziness?!
そんな手抜きが
許されるとでも思ってんのか！
もっと ﾏｼﾞﾒにやれ～！
Do it right!
[A pollen allergy sweeps across Edo. Apparently, a plant from another planet is the cause.]
[I'm exhausted, achoo! I worked too hard thinking the end was near. (laugh)]
["Do Cherries Come from Cherry Trees?"]
Buekushon!
ぶぇっ ぶぇっ… ぶぇくしょん!!
Hakushon!
(新八)ﾊｸｼｮﾝ！
(神楽)ﾏｲｹﾙｼﾞｬｸｼｮﾝ!!
Michael Jackson!
おい ﾏｲｹﾙ･ｼﾞｬｸｿﾝはないだろう…｡
Hey, that can't be Michael Jackson. That was a sneeze.
それは お前 くしゃみじゃ…
ｼﾞｬﾈｯﾄ･ｼﾞｬｸｿﾝ！
It's Janet Jackson!
ﾏｴﾀﾞ･ﾀｲｿﾝ！
うるせえよ！ 普通にしろ!!
Maeda Taison!
[Note: A possible word play on Mike Tyson]
Cut it out! Sneeze normally!
あぁ ﾑｽﾞﾑｽﾞする｡
It's so irritating.
今年の花粉は
例年にも増して ひどいなぁ｡
The pollen this year is worse than normal.
もう街じゅう みんな花粉症で
ｸﾞｼﾞｭｸﾞｼﾞｭのﾃﾞﾛｯﾃﾞﾛになってますよ｡
Everyone on the street is sniffling and suffering from the pollen. I wonder why.
どうなってんすかねぇ？
Seems it's not cedar pollen.
ｽｷﾞ花粉じゃねえらしいや｡
今年は なんか
どこかの星の植物らしくて➡
This year, they think it's a nasty pollen from a plant from another planet.
ﾀﾁ悪いらし… ｼｪｹﾅﾍﾞｲﾋﾞｰ！
Shakin' the baby!
ちょっと！
｢ｿﾝ｣縛りが外れてますよ!!
Hey! Stick to the topic!
いいんだよ！
なんたって この作品は…｡
That's okay, after all, this show is...
(神楽/銀時)ﾌｨｯｸｼｮﾝ！
です…｡
Fiction!
実際の人物 団体 事件など
一切 関係ありません！
No relation to actual persons, groups or events.
よけいな気を
まわさんでいいわ！ 今さら!!
Don't worry about unnecessary things! It's too late!
今さらかよ…｡
なんか 下のﾊﾞﾊﾞｧもよ➡
Too late, you say?
I heard the old hag closed the shop and crawled into bed.
寝込んじまって
店 休んでるらしいよ｡
お登勢さんが!?
あの お登勢さんがですか？
Otose-san? The Otose? You'd think she'd just sprinkle the pollen on her rice for flavor. The Otose?!
どっちかっていうと
花粉を ふりかけに➡
ご飯でも食べてそうな
あの お登勢さんが!?
気持はわかる…
そのくらい ひどいって話だ｡
I know how you feel. I heard it's that bad.
We should probably stay indoors.
そりゃあ あんまり
家 出ないほうがいいですね｡
あっ ﾃｨｯｼｭ切れた！
新八 買ってこいよ!!
We're out of tissues. Shinpachi, go buy some.
おい！ 話 聞いてた？
(神楽)いいから買ってこいよ｡
Hey! Were you even listening?
Never mind, just go buy some. Buying tissues is all you're good for, anyway.
どうせ ﾃｨｯｼｭ買ってくるしか
能がないくせに！
なんだと!? ｸｿｱﾏ！
お前 やっぱり 星に帰れ!!
What did you say, damn bitch! Go home to your planet!
ぶぇっくしょん！ あぁ…｡
Doesn't seem like inside or outside makes any difference. Where is this pollen coming from?
なんか もう 内も外も
変わんねえ気がしてきたぜ!!
いったい どこから入ってくんだ？
この花粉｡
意外と近場から来てたりしてな｡
It might be coming from someplace close by. But there aren't many plants in Kabukicho...
いやぁ でも この かぶき町に
植物なんて…｡
うおりゃあ～っ！
お～い… 生きてっか？
うぅっ…｡
Hey, are you still alive?
ん？
Huh? No way.
あれ？ ｳｿ!?
あれ？
(玄関のﾁｬｲﾑ)
Way.
新八 客だよ… 出るよ｡
Shinpachi, someone's here. Get that.
You're crazy. Ordering me around like that!
お前 ﾑﾁｬｸﾁｬだから！
よく命令できるな!!
いいから出るよ｡
客の応対するくらいしか➡
Just get it. Greeting guests is all you're good for.
能がないくせに！
ｸ～ｯ ﾑｶつく!!
You make me so mad! You're a champion at that! Bitch!
ﾑｶつきﾁｬﾝﾋﾟｵﾝだよ このｱﾏ！
いませんよ 居留守ですよ～！
(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
Nobody's home. We're here, but we're not.
正々堂々か！
So brazen!
Coming, coming, I'll be right there.
はい！ はいはい はい!!
今 出ますよ！
なんで ﾎﾞｸばっかり…｡
Tsk, why is it always me?
(屁怒絽)どうも はじめまして…｡
How do you do? I just moved in next door behind your house.
裏隣に今度 越してきました…➡
屁怒絽です｡
The name's Hedoro.
放屁の屁に怒りの怒➡
It's written "He" as in fart, "do" as in angry, and "ro" as in Robinmask.
ﾛﾋﾞﾝﾏｽｸの絽と書いて
屁怒絽です｡
Hedoro.
(屁怒絽)今日は
ご挨拶に あがりました｡
I've come today to introduce myself.
ﾎﾞｸ 花屋をやってまして➡
I run a flower shop. Please accept this as token of my goodwill.
お近づきのしるしに
これ どうぞ｡
いろいろ ご迷惑を
おかけするかもしれませんが➡
I may be a bother at times,
何とぞ よろしくお願いします｡
but please be good to me.
では おじゃましました！
Well, sorry to bother you.
怖え～っ!!
怖えよ！ なんだよ あれはよ!!
Scary!
Scary! What was that?! Our neighbor Hedoro. Freaky scary!
[Note: A play on "My Neighbor Totoro"]
隣の屁怒絽 めっちゃ怖え！
おい ひょっとして あれか!?
あれ ｢ﾍﾄﾞﾛの森｣か？ おい！
You think, maybe, that's Hedoro's forest?!
うわっ 何すか？ あれ｡ めっちゃ
花粉 飛ばしてるじゃないすか！
What's with that? He's releasing all kinds of pollen into the air.
江戸の花粉症騒ぎは
あれが元凶だったのか…｡
Well, this explains Edo's pollen allergy epidemic.
どうりで みんな
ほったらかしにしてるはずだ！
No wonder no one does anything about it. If they complain, he'd probably kill them.
ｸﾚｰﾑつけてたら殺されそうだもん｡
おいおい とんでもねえのが
引っ越してきちまったな｡
Hey, why's that guy have to move in next to us?
でも お花屋さんって言ってたよ｡
But he said he was a florist.
ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえよ！
Don't be ridiculous!
どう見ても あの面
地球征服しにきた面だろうが！
No matter how you look at him, that face is here to conquer Earth!
昼間は花屋で
夜は 本業の地球征服してんだよ｡
During the day, he's a florist. But at night, he works on his real job of world domination.
This is way worse than good girl by day, naughty girl by night.
昼間は淑女で 夜は
悪女どころじゃねえぞ こりゃ！
He intends to conquer Earth after weakening the people with pollen.
花粉で 人々 弱らせてから➡
地球征服するつもりなんだよ｡
ﾏｼﾞでか！
あっ そういえば…｡
Seriously?
Come to think of it,
さっき
花を置いていったけど あれ…｡
didn't he leave a potted flower. There...
(銀時たち)うわぁ～！
あっ 定春！
Sadaharu!
Sadaharu! Come here quickly! It's going to explode!
定春 早く来るｱﾙ 爆発するよ！
えっ 爆発すんの!?
定春のことは あきらめろ！
What? It's gonna explode?!
Forget about Sadaharu. If we don't hurry, poison gas will...
早くしねえと 毒ｶﾞｽが！
えっ 毒ｶﾞｽ 出るの!?
What? Poison gas?!
定春～！
Sadaharu! I can't just leave him in there!!
そんな
ここで お別れなんて ひどいよ！
花に嵐のたとえもあるさ！
He's a flower in a storm.
Life is all about farewells.
さよならだけが人… うおっ！
Neighborhood Notebook.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)回覧板で～す｡
ﾌﾝｯ！
ｷｬｻﾘﾝ ﾃﾒｴ➡
For god's sake, Catherine!
This is no time to be circulating the Neighborhood Notebook!
回覧板なんて 回してる
場合じゃねえだろうが！
Earth's about to be taken over!
地球が
征服されるかも しれねえんだぞ！
Huh? Did your snot infect your brains? Idiots.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)はぁ？ 鼻水が
脳みそにまで回ったのか？
ｱﾎ！
ぎ… 銀さん 大変だ！
What?! Gin-san, trouble!
Next house on the list is our neighbor Hedoro-san!
回覧板 次 隣の屁怒絽さん家だ！
ｳｿ…｡
You're kidding...
(鼻歌)
He really is a florist.
ﾎﾝﾄに 花屋やってますよ｡
Who'd come to buy from him? Such a scary shop.
誰が買いに来るんだよ
あんな おっかねえ店｡
But he seems to be having so much fun.
でも なんか すごく楽しそうｱﾙ｡
とても 地球を
征服しにきたようには見えないよ｡
He doesn't look at all like he's here to conquer Earth.
Of course he's happy.
そりゃ 楽しいだろうよ｡
He's growing devil flowers that will be the vanguard troops to conquer Earth.
地球征服の尖兵たる
悪魔の花を 育ててんだからな｡
More importantly, how will we pass him the Neighborhood Notebook?
それより どうやって
回覧板を渡しましょう｡
Rock!
ｼﾞｬｰﾝ…｡
ｹｰﾝ…｡
(３人)ﾎﾟﾝ！
Paper!
Scissors!
ぐわっ ﾏｼﾞすか？
うわっ ﾎﾞｸっすか!?
No way! It's me?
直接 渡す必要はねえ｡
You don't have to hand it to him personally.
いくらなんでも
そこまで危険なﾏﾈはな｡
You don't have to do anything dangerous. Act like Passerby A and leave it as you walk by.
通行人Ａのふりして
通り過ぎざまに➡
回覧板を置き去ってこい｡
W-Wait a minute!
ちょっと待って！
通行人Ａったって➡
There's no Passerby A, or B or C or D.
Ｂも Ｃも Ｄも
いないじゃないっすか｡
Everyone's too scared to walk around. Passerby A will clearly stand out big time.
怖がって 誰も歩いてねえよ｡
あきらかに Ａが浮くよ｡
浮きまくりだよ！
Don't sweat it. There'll be passersby.
心配すんな 通行人ならいるさ｡
ちゃ～ん ちゃ～ん！
Chan.
[Note: This is a parody of the manga "Kozure O-Kami" ]
(神楽)ちゃ～ん！
There are no such passersby B and C!
《いねえよ！
そんな通行人ＢとＣ｡
Oh crap! Hedoro's watching. Hedoro's looking right at them!
やばい！ 屁怒絽 見てる｡
屁怒絽 めっちゃ見てるよ～！
B! C! They're being watched! B! C!
Ｂ Ｃ！ 見られてるよ!!
Ｂ Ｃ～!!》
あぁ なんてことでござる｡
What hard luck I've had.
妻が死んでからというもの息子が｡
ちゃ～ん｡
After losing my wife, my son...
Chan.
しか しゃべらなく
なってしまった｡
ちゃ～ん！
This is all he can say.
Chan.
He really means father, not "Chan."
｢ちゃん｣とは 父の意を指す｡
After losing his mother, he's had no one but me to rely on.
母を失って
拙者しか 頼る者のいない今➡
これは しかたなきことだが➡
It can't be helped. But what will I do if he doesn't learn more words? For example...
このまま治らなかったら
どうしよう 例えば…｡
((ちゃ～ん ちゃんちゃんこちゃん
貸してちゃん｡
Chan. Chan chanko chan. Let me chan.
[Note: Chan-chan-ko is like a padded vest.]
え？ 何？ もっかい言って))
What? What? Say that again?
このままじゃ
生活も ままならないぞ｡
Life won't be easy like this.
But I wonder if I should fix it. It feels good to be called "Chan, chan"-I feel like I'm respected.
でも 治すのもなぁ｡
ちゃんちゃん呼ばれるのも
なんか 尊敬されてるみたいで➡
気分いいし｡
どうしようかなぁでござる｡
What should I do?
Father didn't know. Daijiro's only word, "Chan," did not mean "Father."
[Note: This is a spoof of Lone Wolf and Cub.]
＜神楽:父は知らなかった｡
大次郎の口ｸﾞｾ ｢ちゃ～ん｣とは
父の意ではなく➡
母が よく父に言っていた➡
Mother had often told Father:
｢ｱﾝﾀさぁ
もっと ちゃんと働いて！
[Note: Chanto means "work like you're supposed to"]
"You need to chanto! Our budget is really tight."
ﾏｼﾞ 家計きついんだけど｣の
｢ちゃん｣であることを｡
That's what "Chan" meant.
It had nothing to do with Daijiro loving Father or anything like that.
大次郎は 別に父が好きとか
そういうのは全然なかった＞
(神楽)ちゃ～ん｡
Chan.
We don't need any of that superfluous storyline!
《いらねえんだよ
そんな ﾑﾀﾞな設定！
あれ？ 屁怒絽 泣いてる？》
Huh? Is Hedoro crying?!
よく わかんないけど 今だ！
I'm not quite sure, but now's my chance!
うおぉ～！ 回覧板で～す!!
Here's the Neighborhood Notebook!
♪♪～
うぉ～…｡
This is trouble, big trouble, humongous trouble.
やばいよ めっさ やばいよ｡
ごっさ やばいよ｡
包丁 研いでるよ
日本昔話みたいになってるよ｡
He's sharpening his knife. It's like a Japanese fairy tale.
ちゃ～ん 私たち
食べられちゃうのちゃ～ん？
Chan. Will we be eaten up, chan?
(屁怒絽)いや～ 回覧板くらいで
わざわざ ３人で来ていただいて➡
My, I appreciate all three of you coming all the way out here
just to bring the Neighborhood Notebook.
すいませんねぇ｡
Please make yourselves at home. I'll prepare something to snack on.
ゆっくりしていってください｡
今 軽く つまめるものを
用意いたしますので｡
《３人:つままれる！
He's going to snack on us!
このままでは 確実に
つままれる!!》
He's definitely going to snack on us!
Uh...er...um...Hedoro-san, I mean Hedoro-sama.
あ あの… 屁怒絽さん
いや 屁怒絽様！
(屁怒絽)いや
屁怒絽でいいですよ｡
No, just plain Hedoro is fine.
Uh...I'm sorry about earlier.
あの さっき すみませんでした｡
か… 回覧板 ぶつけちゃって｡
I hit you with the notebook.
The strap on my sandal thong broke and... I know this sounds like an excuse, but it's the truth.
草履の鼻緒が切れてしまって｡
言い訳くさいですけど ﾎﾝﾄで｡
No, forget it. It was an accident. An accident.
(屁怒絽)いやぁ いいんですよ
事故ですよ 事故｡
More importantly, don't they say a sandal thong breaking is a bad omen?
それより 鼻緒が切れるって
不吉の予兆というではないですか｡
何か よからぬことが
起こらなければいいのですが｡
I hope nothing bad happens.
He's about to do something evil.
《よからぬことを
しようとしている！》
He's about to bring us bad luck.
《３人:不吉を
起こそうとしている!!》
Uh...Hedoro-sama? I mean Duke Hedoro.
あ あの… 屁怒絽様？
い いや 屁怒絽伯爵？
No, just Hedoro will do.
(屁怒絽)いや
屁怒絽でいいですよ｡
Uh...we appreciate you entertaining us,
あの～ おもてなししてくれるのは
嬉しいんですが➡
but I just received word that my father is in critical condition, so we have to leave immediately...
さっき 父が危篤との連絡が
入りまして➡
すぐに帰らなきゃ…｡
(屁怒絽)なんですって！
What?
どうして
早く言ってくれないんですか？
Why didn't you say so sooner?
I'm concerned, too. Would you mind if I came along?
あの 心配なんで
ﾎﾞｸも行っていいですか？
《ついてくるつもりだ！》
He plans on coming with us!
He plans to follow us to the depths of hell and put us in critical condition.
《神楽:地獄の底まで
ついてきて…》
He's planning to put us in critical condition.
《銀時たち:ｵﾚたちを
危篤にするつもりだ！》
Uh...no, it's all right. Dad was a rotten father anyway.
あの やっぱり いいです｡
結構
どうでもいい親父だったんで｡
What? Is that so? And just when I thought I'd bring some of my flowers as a get-well gift.
(屁怒絽)えぇっ そうなんですか？
せっかく ｳﾁの花を持って➡
お見舞いに行こうと思ったのに｡
No, really, it doesn't matter. In fact, I'm hoping the funeral comes quickly.
いや ﾎﾝﾄ もう どうでもいいです｡
むしろ 早く葬式あげたいなぁ
くらいで｡
Is that so? By all means, please use my flowers for the funeral.
(屁怒絽)そうですか
お葬式の際は➡
ぜひ ｳﾁの花を使ってください｡
I grew these flowers with my heart and soul.
精魂込めて育てた花ですから➡
I'm sure they'll lead your father to the land of Perfect Bliss.
きっと お父様を 極楽浄土へ
導いてくれるはずです｡
《導かれる》
Lead him to?
Not just his father, but the entire planet.
《神楽:お父様だけでなく
地球全員が！》
《極楽浄土に導かれる！》
He's leading us to the land of Perfect Bliss!
Hedoro-san, why did you become a florist?
あの 屁怒絽さんって
どうして お花屋さんなんか？
(屁怒絽)ん？
ﾊﾊ… 似合わないでしょ｡
I don't look the part, do I?
No, that wasn't what I meant...
いや そういう意味じゃ…｡
(屁怒絽)ﾊﾊﾊ… いいんです
自分でも わかってますから｡
It's all right. I'm fully aware of it! Especially because of the way I look...
こんな見てくれじゃあねぇ｡
ﾎﾞｸはね 花になりたいんです｡
I've always wished I could be a flower.
People always feared me because of the way I look.
(屁怒絽)昔から
こんな外見のために➡
他人から怖がられていたものでね｡
So I thought I'd make at least my heart as nice as a flower.
せめて 心だけでも
花のように きれいになりたいと｡
だから 少しでも 花と
近くにいられる仕事がしたくて｡
That's why I want to be as close as possible to flowers.
But it seems it doesn't fit me, after all. I haven't had a single customer yet.
でも
やっぱり 向いてないみたいだ｡
お客様なんて 一人も来ないもの｡
Sakata-san, you and your friends are the only ones who weren't afraid of me.
坂田さんたちだけですよ｡
怖がらずに
ﾎﾞｸと接してくれたのは｡
Sorry, but...
《すいません》
《３人:ﾒﾁｬﾒﾁｬ 怖いんですけど》
We're absolutely frightened of you.
銀さん ひょっとして屁怒絽さん➡
Gin-san... Do you think maybe Hedoro-san is actually a nice person?
ﾎﾝﾄは いい人なんじゃ…｡
No. The "Gap Rule" applies.
違うな あれは ｷﾞｬｯﾌﾟﾙｰﾙ｡
ｷﾞｬｯﾌﾟﾙｰﾙ？
"Gap Rule"?
ふだんは
ﾘｰｾﾞﾝﾄで突っ張っているﾔﾂが➡
When someone with a ducktail hairstyle
たま～に いいことしたりすると➡
does something nice once in a while, his image goes up.
ものすご～く 好感度が上がる｡
Contrarily, when someone who is ordinarily nice
しか～し 反面
ふだん いい子ちゃんでいるﾔﾂが➡
does something even a little wrong, he becomes a villain.
ちょ～っと 悪いことをすると➡
むっちゃくっちゃ
悪いように見える｡
That's the "Gap Rule".
それが ｷﾞｬｯﾌﾟﾙｰﾙだ｡
ちょ～っと！
So, what do you think I am?! That makes me a devil in human skin!
ﾎﾞｸを なんだと思ってんの!?
それじゃ➡
人の皮かぶった ﾃﾞﾋﾞﾙじゃん!!
Which means, Hedoro is actually...
ってことは ﾎﾝﾄは 屁怒絽も…｡
Wrong! He looks nothing if not hungry! Tonight's dinner is meow-burger.
違～う！
食う絵にしか 見えねえだろ！
今夜のﾃﾞｨﾅｰは ﾆｬﾝﾊﾞｰｸﾞだよ！
You guys are too easily fooled when his appearance doesn't match his actions.
だいたい ﾃﾒｴらは 外見と➡
ちょっと 落差ができたからって
ｺﾛｯと だまされすぎなんだよ！
人は 見かけによらねえなんて
言葉は 世間知らずの妄言だ｡
"You can't trust a book by its cover" is what stupid people say. First impressions...
大事だよ 第一印象は！
are what you need to believe! Be inspired. Feel with imagination!
信じるんだ ｲﾝｽﾋﾟﾚｰｼｮﾝ｡
感じるんだ ｲﾏｼﾞﾈｰｼｮﾝ！
は～い 神楽｡ あの お釜の中➡
Okay, Kagura! What do you think will be in that pot in a few hours?
数時間後 どうなってると思う!?
Uh...lots of hot rice?
(神楽)え～っと…
ﾎｸﾎｸご飯で いっぱいよ｡
ちっが～う!!
これだから困るんだよ お子様は！
Wrong! This is where we have a problem!
今から 正解 見せっから！
I'll show you the correct answer!
[A few hours later]
Oh! I think it's just about ready.
おっ そろそろ煮えたかな？
(２人)ひぇぇ～っ!!
Did you see it? Could you see it? What our future looks like?
なっ 見えた？ 見えちゃった？
ｵﾚたちの 未来予想図｡
It's pitch black. No headlights or anything!
真っ暗だよ…｡
ﾍｯﾄﾞﾗｲﾄもｸｿもねえ！
Forgive me for keeping you waiting. I'm not very good at this.
すみません お待たせしちゃって｡
手際が悪いものですから｡
いやいや いや… ごゆっくり！
永久に ごゆっくり～！
No, no, no take your time. Take forever.
(屁怒絽)あの…
横になってくださって➡
Feel free to lie down. Make yourselves at home.
かまいませんから｡
自分の家だと思って➡
くつろいでください｡
準備ができたら 起こしますので｡
When I'm done, I'll wake you up.
Shinpachi! You know what that means, don't you? What'll happen if we fall asleep?
《新八～ わかってんな！
寝たら どうなるか！》
《はい～っ！
寝たら襲われ 釜の中！
Yes! If we fall asleep, we'll be attacked and end up in the pot! We'll be in the miso soup!
ﾎﾞｸたち ｲﾝ ｻﾞ みそｽｰﾌﾟ！》
Hey!
って おい～っ!!
おい～っ!!
Huh? The more you say not to fall asleep, the sleepier I become.
あれ？
寝ちゃﾀﾞﾒだと思えば思うほど➡
眠気が強くなる
試験の前の日ﾙｰﾙ？
Is this like what happens the day before a test?
わかってるなら 寝るな～っ!!
If you're aware of it, don't fall asleep!
もはや ｵﾚたちには
一刻の猶予もない｡
We have no time to lose.
I'll create a diversion to draw his attention! You run like hell!
ｵﾚが ﾔﾂを引きつける！
その間に お前らは逃げろ！
銀さん！
Gin-san.
あれを見ろ｡
あれは…｡
Look at that.
That's...
JUMP...used to keep his fridge level?
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣を敷いて…
冷蔵庫の高さを調節して…｡
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣はな 男たちが
夢と冒険に 心をふるわせる本だ｡
JUMP stirs the dreams and adventurous spirit of all men.
それを あんな使い方するﾔﾂに➡
Anyone who treats it like that
is evil!
いいﾔﾂなんて いねえ!!
What kind of reasoning is that?!
なに～!? その理由!!
でやぁぁ～っ!!
むっ!?
(爆発音)
(屁怒絽)大丈夫ですか？
坂田さん｡
Are you all right, Sakata-san?
That was close...
いや～ 危なかった｡
You were just about to step on a ladybug. Killing is wrong.
危うく てんとう虫を
踏むところでしたよ｡
殺生は いけない｡
(神楽/新八)うわぁ～っ!!
(屁怒絽)あ～ ﾀﾞﾒだよ ｷﾐたちも｡
Watch where you're going, you two.
危うく 植木を倒すところだった｡
You nearly knocked over these daisies.
殺生は いけないってば！
Killing is wrong.
心の力を ください…｡
Give me inner strength...
Inner strength...
心の力を ください！
Hedoro!
屁怒絽～!!
地球は お前に 渡さねえ!!
We're not letting you
take over the Earth!
(神楽)いやぁぁぁ～っ!!
Gin-san, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I gave in.
銀さん ごめん！ ごめんよ!!
ﾎﾞｸは ﾍﾀﾚだ！
銀さんを犠牲に
生き延びることしか考えてない！
All I can think of is sacrificing you so I can survive.
死ぬか生きるかの瀬戸際に➡
どかんかい うぉりゃ～っ！
Out of my way!
I can't worry about others when my life hangs in the balance!
他人のことなんざ
かまっとれるかい!!
That's totally cruel!
そんな 身も蓋もない！
銀ちゃん➡
Just tell him, "Gin-chan, I'll live your share for you, so rest in peace"!
ｱﾝﾀの分まで 生きたるわ
成仏してやくらい➡
言っとけばええんじゃ～!!
黒い！ 黒いよ ｱﾝﾀ～!!
You're sinister. Sinister, I say!
来た～！ 来よったで～!!
He's coming! He's coming!
ってことは 銀さんは もう…！
Which means, Gin-san is already...
いやぁぁぁ～っ!!
No!
銀さん!? ちょっと 地球は!?
地球を守るんじゃなかったの～!?
Gin-san? What about the Earth?! Weren't you going to protect Earth?
地球より 自分じゃ～!!
なに それ～!?
My life before Earth!
What's with that?!
♪♪～
なんだ この家!? 出口 どこ～!?
What's with this house?! Where's the exit?
罠よ！ この家自体が 罠よ!!
It's a trap. The house itself is a trap!
あそこ！ あそこよ～!!
There! Over there!
ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ… ぬほっ!!
Ow ow...
どうした？ 新八！
あっ… あれ…｡
What's the matter, Shinpachi?
O-Over there...
An altar!
祭壇!!
ですよね!? 祭壇ですよね!?
It is, isn't it? An altar. A sacrificial altar, right there.
生け贄に 捧げるんですよね
あそこに!!
No! I don't want to die yet!
(神楽)ｲﾔよ～！
私 死にたくない～!!
でも なんで 祭壇なんか…？
ﾊﾞｶ野郎 決まってんだろ！
But why is there an altar here?
Idiot! It's obvious.
It's to make a pact with the Devil and achieve eternal life.
悪魔と契約して
永遠の命を得るためだよ！
(神楽)そうよ！
永遠に ｲﾉｷになるためよ！
[Bedroom]
That's right. Eternal leaf...
(３人)あわわわわ…！
(屁怒絽)坂田さん！
どこ行ったんですか？
Sakata-san, where did you go?
おかしいなぁ…➡
That's odd. I thought I heard something around here.
こっちから
物音が聞こえたんだけどなぁ…｡
(屁怒絽)聞き間違いかなぁ｡
早く 見つけないと…｡
Maybe I was wrong. I have to find them quickly.
ここじゃなかったのか…｡
So they weren't here...
ふぇっ…！
見つけましたよ｡
(３人)うおぉ～っ!!
I found you!
逃げろ～!!
Run!
やだ～！
童貞のまま死ぬのは やだ～!!
No! I don't want to die a virgin!
新八！ お前が 犠牲になれば
すべては 丸く収まるね!!
Shinpachi! If you sacrifice yourself, everything will be okay!
なに それ!? 勝手に決めるな～!!
What?! Don't decide that by yourself!
お前の分まで
ｵﾚたちが 生きてやる!!
We'll live your share for you!
You're saying the same thing!
同じこと言ってるよ ｱﾝﾀら！
あっ…｡
ちょっと～!!
上 来ちゃってるよ！
Wait!
He's coming! Climbing up!
上っちゃってますよ!!
だったら 下りろ!!
Then go down!
By yourself!
(神楽)１人でな～!!
ｱﾝﾀら 鬼ですか～!!
Are you people demons?!
鬼は あれだ～!!
待ってくださ～い!!
That's the demon!
Please wait!
(２人)鬼だ～!!
The demon!
Look there! A way out!
あれ 見ろ～！ 出口だ～!!
♪♪～
な… なに これ～!?
What's this?!
こ… こんなに 高かったっけ？
Were we this high up?
Sakata-san.
(屁怒絽)坂田さ～ん!!
いや～ やっと 追いつきました｡
I finally caught up with you.
Shinpachi. Kagura. It's been nice knowing you...
新八 神楽…
短い つきあいだったな｡
Gin-san...
銀さん…？
銀ちゃん…｡
Gin-chan...
３人 同時に行けば ﾒは ある…｡
If the three of us team up, then we'll have a chance.
最後は 決めっか｡
Let's end this right.
江戸の街を…
地球を守りましょう｡
Let's protect the city of Edo...and the Earth.
Yes. That's the one last thing we can do.
そうね｡ それが 私たちにできる
唯一のことｱﾙ！
いくぜ!!
おぅ!!
はい!!
Let's go!
Okay!
(３人)でやぁぁ～っ!!
Oh, a drone beetle.
あっ ｶﾅﾌﾞﾝだ｡ えっ？
(３人)えっ？ うわぁ～っ！
よかった…｡
大丈夫ですか？ 皆さん｡
I'm glad... Are you all okay?
(３人)
…はい ありがとうございます｡
Yes.
Thank you very much.
＜ それからも
地球は 征服されることなどなく➡
And from that day on, Earth lived on peacefully and was not conquered.
相変わらず 平和だった｡
江戸の街にも
相変わらず 花粉が舞い続けた｡
And in the streets of Edo, the pollen continued to swirl about.
ただ１つ
変わったことといえば…＞
If there was one thing that did change...
ﾌｪ… ﾌｪ… ﾌｪｯｸｼｮﾝ！
ﾊｸｼｮﾝ！
Fekkushon!
Hakkushon!
ﾏｼﾞｯｸ･ｼﾞｮﾝｿﾝ！
ﾊｸｼｮﾝ！
Magic Johnson!
Hakkushon!
ﾊｸｼｮﾝ！
ｾﾄｳﾁ･ｼﾞｬｸｿﾝ!
Setouchi Jackson!
[Note: A character in the series "Cromartie High School"]
Edith Hanson!
[Note: An American personality on Japanese television]
ｲｰﾃﾞｽ･ﾊﾝｿﾝ！
ﾍﾞﾝ･ｼﾞｮﾝｿﾝ！
Ben Johnson!
＜ いつもは騒がしい万事屋から➡
For a while, the only sound one could hear from the normally raucous Odd Jobs was sneezing.
しばらくの間 くしゃみの音しか
しなかったことである＞
ん～っふ｡
[Preview]
I feel horrible.
Why am I running into that guy everywhere on my day off?
Why is that?
The next episode... "The More You're Alike, the More You Fight."
[The other story is about the "Kick the Can" game. Why is it that once you try it, you can't stand to lose at it?]
[Just two more episodes in season one of Gin Tama the anime. We'll hit the hot spa and give it one last go!]
わわ… わぁ 落ちる！
舌を噛むわよ！
しゃべっちゃﾀﾞﾒ！
ｾﾚﾅ あなたは 今 ｻｲﾎｰﾝなのよ！
無茶 言わないでよ！
ﾏﾏも そうやって
ｻｲﾎｰﾝﾚｰｽの世界で戦ってきたの！
ｾﾚﾅもできる！
当たって砕けろよ！
もう やだ～！